VIKTOR MARTIN

Full Stack Developer

@ viktorsh818@gmail.com

♦ 13 Tampines St. 11, Singapore Singapore 529453

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack developer with more than five years of experience. I have always been customer satisfaction-oriented and continue to apply my knowledge to deliver tangible results in a timely manner. During my career, I fall in love with web development in general—the React and Next.js for front-end development, Django and Node.js for back-end development, and DevOps technologies. Additionally, I enjoy working with Data Structures and Algorithms.

EDUCATION

09/2013 - 05/2017

Singapore, Singapore

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Singapore Institute of Technology

GPA 3.9 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

01/2018 - Present

Freelance Developer

Remote

Freelancer

- · Developed and deployed full-stack products and applications for clients.
- · Provided programming instruction to clients, helping them to develop their skills and achieve their goals in software development.
- · Gained experience with various technology stacks, including new technologies such as blockchain.

01/2018 - 05/2023

SIngapore, Singapore

Full Stack Developer

Guidewire Software

- · Developed user interface using React for SPA development.
- · Created reusable and scalable React components using state management libraries like Redux and Recoil.
- Utilized Redux Saga and Thunk middleware libraries to handle complex asynchronous workflows and side effects, providing enhanced control and organization to the codebase
- Added real-time communication and data updates to React components using WebSockets, and managed state efficiently with Redux.
- · Utilized Django and Node.js for back-end development, integrated third-party APIs including Twilio.
- Used Firebase and Strapi to improve the app's functionality, manage data efficiently, boost performance, and provide a great user experience.
- Used GraphQL with Django and React Apollo to make data fetching faster and seamlessly connect the backend and frontend.
- · Implemented CI/CD with the deployment to server.
- · Used Next.js 13 to build React applications that render on the server and generate static page, ensuring optimal performance and enhanced user experiences.
- · Managed a team of two people to develop and deploy a full-stack application in Next.js, Django, GraphQL, and DynamoDB to AWS.
- · Researched users and customers to iterate on the product based on feedback.

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript TypeScript Python PHP 7 Java GraphQL Solidity

Libraries/APIs

React Node.js Web3.js

Frameworks

Next.js React Native Django Django Rest Framework Express.js Laravel

Storage

MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB Amazon DynamoDB

Paradigms

Automation REST Management

STRENGTHS



Problem-solving

Quickly identify and solve complex problems, resulting in 30% improvement in application performance.



Collaboration

Work effectively in team environments, resulting in on time project delivery and improved customer satisfaction.